<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Julia Vonessen on mowery.dev</title><link>https://mowery.dev/author/julia-vonessen/</link><description>Recent content in Julia Vonessen on mowery.dev</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mowery.dev/author/julia-vonessen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Brigadeiros</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/brigadeiros/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/brigadeiros/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 Tbsp cocoa powder 1 Tbsp butter 14 oz sweetened condensed milk Chocolate sprinkles or crystal sugar Instructions In a medium saucepan over medium heat, combine cocoa, butter and condensed milk Cook, stirring the entire time, until thickened enough to show the pan bottom during stirring, about 10 minutes. When the pan is tipped, the mixture should appear to be loose from the pan Remove from heat and pour into a lightly greased dish Let rest until cool enough to handle, about two minutes Form into small balls (with greased hands) and roll over sprinkles or crystal sugar Place the balls in small candy cups and eat at once or chill until serving</description></item><item><title>Cheesecake (Julia)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/cheesecake/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/cheesecake/</guid><description>Ingredients Number of recipes: Crust 2 cups finely ground graham crackers (about 30 squares) 1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon 1 stick unsalted butter, melted Filling 1 pound cream cheese, softened 3 eggs 1 cup sugar 1 pint sour cream 1 lemon, zested 1 dash vanilla extract Warm Lemon Blueberries 1 pint blueberries 1 lemon, zested and juiced 2 tablespoons sugar Instructions Preheat the oven to 325 degrees F Crust In a mixing bowl, combine the ingredients with a fork until evenly moistened.</description></item></channel></rss>