<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>breakfast on mowery.dev</title><link>https://mowery.dev/tags/breakfast/</link><description>Recent content in breakfast on mowery.dev</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mowery.dev/tags/breakfast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>French Toast</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/french_toast/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/french_toast/</guid><description> Info
This recipe involves leaving the bread in the fridge overnight, plan accordingly
Equipment Requires a large pan (10x15) Ingredients 6 Le Petit Outre Kaiser Rolls (top and bottom crust removed) 6 eggs 2 cups of milk 3/8 cup sugar 1/2 tsp salt 1 Tbsp Vanilla 2 Tbsp Butter (cut into thin slices) Cinnamon (to taste) Instructions Grease pan; place the bread Beat eggs, sugar, salt, vanilla Pour the mixture on the bread Leave overnight in fridge Turn the bread around (so the top gets moister) Sprinkle Cinnamon Put thin slices of butter on top Bake for about 40 minutes (to an hour) on 350 F (325 F if on a glass dish)</description></item><item><title>Brigadeiros</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/brigadeiros/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/brigadeiros/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 Tbsp cocoa powder 1 Tbsp butter 14 oz sweetened condensed milk Chocolate sprinkles or crystal sugar Instructions In a medium saucepan over medium heat, combine cocoa, butter and condensed milk Cook, stirring the entire time, until thickened enough to show the pan bottom during stirring, about 10 minutes. When the pan is tipped, the mixture should appear to be loose from the pan Remove from heat and pour into a lightly greased dish Let rest until cool enough to handle, about two minutes Form into small balls (with greased hands) and roll over sprinkles or crystal sugar Place the balls in small candy cups and eat at once or chill until serving</description></item><item><title>Cheesecake (Julia)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/cheesecake/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/cheesecake/</guid><description>Ingredients Number of recipes: Crust 2 cups finely ground graham crackers (about 30 squares) 1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon 1 stick unsalted butter, melted Filling 1 pound cream cheese, softened 3 eggs 1 cup sugar 1 pint sour cream 1 lemon, zested 1 dash vanilla extract Warm Lemon Blueberries 1 pint blueberries 1 lemon, zested and juiced 2 tablespoons sugar Instructions Preheat the oven to 325 degrees F Crust In a mixing bowl, combine the ingredients with a fork until evenly moistened.</description></item><item><title>Tortillas</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/tortillas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/tortillas/</guid><description>Ingredients 10g oil 100g flour 55g water 1.5-2g salt (1/4 tsp) Instructions Mix all ingredients, oil first Roll out Cook</description></item><item><title>Banana Bread (Grandma Lonergan's)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/banana_bread_matt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/banana_bread_matt/</guid><description>See original at matt9j.net/recipes/banana-bread
True origins unknown, but refined over many generations, this recipe makes a delicious soft banana bread. For maximum enjoyment be sure to not over-cook it, avoid over-mixing once you&amp;rsquo;ve combined the dry and wet ingredients, and consider adding some dark chocolate chips or favorite chopped nuts!
0: Prework: Preheat oven to 325 Lightly grease 9x5 loaf pan 1: In a large bowl mix: 2 cups flour 1 tsp baking soda ½ tsp baking powder ½ tsp salt 2: In a separate bowl mix: 1 ½ cup mashed overripe bananas (3-4) ¾ cup sugar ¾ cup vegetable oil 2 eggs 2 T vanilla (that is not a typo&amp;hellip; two tablespoons is correct) 3: Put it all together: Stir banana mixture into flour mixture; stir just to moisten.</description></item><item><title>Banana Bread (Laura)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/banana_bread_laura/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/banana_bread_laura/</guid><description>Original
Prework: Preheat oven to 325 Lightly grease 9x5 loaf pan
In a large bowl mix: 2 cups flour 1 tsp baking soda ½ tsp baking powder ½ tsp salt 1 T cinnamon In a separate bowl mix: 1½ cup mashed overripe bananas (3-4) 1/3 cup sugar ¾ cup vegetable oil 2 eggs 1 T vanilla Optionally some other fruit (e.g. 1-2 apples) cut small Put it all together: Stir banana mixture into flour mixture; stir just to moisten.</description></item><item><title>Lime Mousse Pie</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/lime_mousse_pie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/lime_mousse_pie/</guid><description>Notes This recipe makes 2 8-inch pies or 1 9-inch pie. Ingredients 1.5 cups of graham crackers 6 tbsp butter 1/3 cup sugar Ingredients for Lime Mousse Instructions Food process the graham crackers into a fine crumble, then dump the crumbs into a mixing bowl Food process the butter and sugar together, then add them to the graham crackers Pat the mixture into a pie tin Follow the recipe for the lime mousse, then pour the result over the pie tin Let set in the freezer Images</description></item><item><title>Plum Cake (Pflaumenkuchen)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/plum_cake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/plum_cake/</guid><description>Notes: For historical reasons this is named &amp;ldquo;Plum Cake&amp;rdquo; but it is actually a pie. This is our version of Pflaumenkuchen. Ingredients Wet ingredients 1 stick butter (1/2 cup) 1 egg 2/3c sugar Dry ingredients 1 1/2c flour 1/2 Tbsp baking powder 1 pinch salt 1/2 cinnamon Plums 1.5 lbs italian plums, halved The topping 1 tsp cinnamon 1/4c hazelnuts (After baking, optional) 1 Tbsp cane sugar Instructions Preheat oven to 375*F.</description></item></channel></rss>