<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Florence Fabricant on mowery.dev</title><link>https://mowery.dev/author/florence-fabricant/</link><description>Recent content in Florence Fabricant on mowery.dev</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 20:52:22 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mowery.dev/author/florence-fabricant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Strawberry Rhubarb Pie</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/strawberry_rhubarb_pie/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/strawberry_rhubarb_pie/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/srp_2.webp" alt="Strawberry Rhubarb Pie">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="for-the-filling">For the Filling&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>3 cups rhubarb in one-inch pieces, about one pound&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 cups strawberry halves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>½ cup sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 tablespoons corn starch or tapioca&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 tablespoons unsalted butter&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="for-the-crust">For the Crust&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2½ cups all-purpose flour, plus more for dusting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>½ teaspoon salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>¾ teaspoon sugar, plus extra for sprinkling&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 5tablespoons unsalted butter (almost 2 sticks), very cold and cut into
¼-inch cubes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>½ cup ice-cold water&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tablespoons milk&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="instructions">Instructions&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Prepare the pastry: combine the flour, salt and sugar in a large mixing bowl.
Using a fork or pastry cutter, work half of the butter into the flour until
it resembles coarse meal. Quickly work the remaining butter into the dough
until the biggest pieces are the size of lima beans. Drizzle in the water in
several additions, tossing and mixing between each. (It should look rather
ropy and rough.) Stop adding water when a few bits of dry flour remain in the
bottom of the bowl; do not overwork the dough or it will become tough. Gather
two-thirds of the dough and wrap tightly with plastic wrap. Do the same with
the remaining third. Flatten into disks. Refrigerate for at least 30 minutes.
When the dough is chilled, roll out the larger piece and line a nine-inch pie
pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If rhubarb is thick, peel it. Combine rhubarb and strawberries in a bowl. Mix
sugar and tapioca together and fold gently into the strawberries and rhubarb.
Allow to macerate for 15 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Preheat oven to 425.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spoon fruit into pastry shell and dot with butter. Roll out remaining pastry,
cut into strips three-quarters of an inch wide and weave a lattice to cover
the pie. You can simply lay the strips on top in criss-cross fashion if
weaving is not one of your skills. Seal, trim and crimp the edges. Brush the
lattice with milk and sprinkle with a bit of sugar.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bake in preheated oven for 20-25 minutes. Lower heat to 350 degrees and bake 40
minutes longer, until pastry has browned and filling begins to bubble. Let
pie cool completely before serving, at least 3 hours and up to overnight to
set the filling.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../images/srp_1.webp" alt="Strawberry Rhubarb Pie">
&lt;img src="../images/srp_3.webp" alt="Strawberry Rhubarb Pie">
&lt;img src="../images/srp_4.webp" alt="Strawberry Rhubarb Pie">
&lt;img src="../images/srp_5.webp" alt="Strawberry Rhubarb Pie">&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>