<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Laura Vonessen on mowery.dev</title><link>https://mowery.dev/author/laura-vonessen/</link><description>Recent content in Laura Vonessen on mowery.dev</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mowery.dev/author/laura-vonessen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hazelnut Macaroons (Nussmakronen)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/hazelnut_macaroons/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/hazelnut_macaroons/</guid><description>Original recipe (in German)
Ingredients 3 egg whites (no yolks!) 150g sugar (3/4 cup) (optional) 2 Tbsp vanilla sugar 250g ground hazelnuts (coarser than flour, but still pretty fine) (optional) whole hazelnuts for decoration parchment paper and/or something to grease a baking sheet with Instructions Preheat the oven to 150°C/300°F (or see step 8) Beat the egg whites a little, then add 1 Tbsp of sugar and beat fully stiff One spoon at a time, add the rest of the sugar (including vanilla sugar), and continue to beat for ~4 more minutes until the consistency is thick Gently fold in the ground hazelnuts (optional) Let the dough sit in the fridge for 30-60 minutes to get stiffer With two teaspoons, make small heaps on a greased and/or parchment-paper-lined baking sheet.</description></item><item><title>Beans (Brazilian)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/beans/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/beans/</guid><description>Equipment Pressure cooker Immersion blender (optional but makes things easier) Notes on pressure cooking The listed time to pressure cook something only starts counting from the moment pressure is achieved With an Instant Pot use high pressure, and make sure you turn the release valve to sealing instead of venting Ingredients Beans 3 cups beans (1 lb), unsoaked 9 cups water (3x cups beans) Seasoning 1 medium onion, diced small 3 cloves garlic, crushed olive oil, to taste salt, to taste 3/4 lb tomatoes, diced small Instructions Wash the beans, removing any rocks or particularly disfigured beans Combine beans and water in pressure cooker and pressure cook for 50 minutes While the beans are cooking, start the seasoning: Saute the onions until translucent, then add the garlic and saute another minute Add the tomatoes and salt and continue sauteing until the mixture has the consistency of a sauce, then set it aside Once the beans have finished pressure cooking, let them sit for 15 minutes to naturally release some of the pressure, then use whatever quick release method is safe to let off remaining pressure In a bowl (a liquid measuring cup works well for this) combine the seasoning and a few ladles of beans/bean broth Mix with the immersion blender, or sort of smash things with a wooden spoon if you don&amp;rsquo;t have one, then pour back into the rest of the beans Taste and adjust salt if necessary Bonus Serve some of the bean broth in shot glasses while it&amp;rsquo;s still hot.</description></item><item><title>Banana Bread (Laura)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/banana_bread_laura/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/banana_bread_laura/</guid><description>Original
Prework: Preheat oven to 325 Lightly grease 9x5 loaf pan
In a large bowl mix: 2 cups flour 1 tsp baking soda ½ tsp baking powder ½ tsp salt 1 T cinnamon In a separate bowl mix: 1½ cup mashed overripe bananas (3-4) 1/3 cup sugar ¾ cup vegetable oil 2 eggs 1 T vanilla Optionally some other fruit (e.g. 1-2 apples) cut small Put it all together: Stir banana mixture into flour mixture; stir just to moisten.</description></item><item><title>Pasta primavera</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/pasta_prima/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/pasta_prima/</guid><description>Notes This is my absolute favorite recipe and a staple of my diet. I&amp;rsquo;ve made it my own over the years; feel free to do the same! The original recipe called for peeling the tomatoes, and left everything to marinate for an hour before the garlic was removed. I&amp;rsquo;ve removed these steps, but the order of operations in this recipe is designed to allow for maximum marination. However, these are guidelines, not rules&amp;ndash;nothing will be ruined if your prep timing lines up differently than the recipe calls for.</description></item><item><title>Waffles</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/waffles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/waffles/</guid><description>Laura&amp;rsquo;s waffle recipe, stolen from ancestors.
The portions here are for 2 people to eat a large breakfast.
If feeding more people double or triple the amounts below.
Equipment Blender Waffle iron that makes hearts Ingredients Number of people eating: Waffle batter 1/2 stick butter 2 eggs 1 pinch salt 1/4 cup sugar 3/4 cup oats 3/4 cup flour 1 cup milk (to right consistency) Mandated toppings Mixed frozen berries compote (no cherries), made by microwaving in a bowl for 3-4 minutes Maple syrup Powdered sugar Instructions Using a high powered blender To make the batter combine all ingredients in a blender and blend until consistent Using a shitty blender or making a larger recipe Cut the butter into pieces, combine with eggs, sugar, and salt in the blender and blend until consistent Add 1/4 cup flour, 1/4 cup oats, and 1/3 cup milk at a time, blend until consistent each time Pictures</description></item></channel></rss>