<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dinner on mowery.dev</title><link>https://mowery.dev/tags/dinner/</link><description>Recent content in dinner on mowery.dev</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 12:46:31 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mowery.dev/tags/dinner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Zucchini Basil Pasta</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/zucchini_basil_pasta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/zucchini_basil_pasta/</guid><description>Original
Ingredients Pasta 4c vegetable broth (standard package size) 16oz pasta (shells work well, standard package size) 4-5 medium zucchini cut into 1/2-inch cubes 8oz mascarpone, crème fraîche or softened cream cheese (standard package size) 1 large garlic clove, crushed 1/6 cup packed thinly sliced basil Salt to taste Cayenne to taste Gremolata 9 tablespoons chopped roasted salted almonds 9 tablespoons chopped Italian parsley 1/2 cup packed thinly sliced basil Salt to taste Instructions Pasta In a 12-inch pot, bring stock to a boil over high heat.</description></item><item><title>Beef Veggie Soup</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/beef_veggie_soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/beef_veggie_soup/</guid><description>(as interpreted by Laura, and then halved)
Ingredients 2.5 lb cubed stew meat or beef shank ½ onion 2 stalks/ribs celery (not 2 heads!) 2 cloves garlic 8 carrots (peeled, 2 in food processor, others in large chunks) (for original double recipe, 10-15 carrots) ½ butternut squash, peeled and cut in cubes (can also use 1 lb pre-cut) 1 large or 2 small sweet potatoes (pale yellow), peeled and cut in cubes 1 lb green beans, cut into halves or thirds and with ends removed For the meat Food-process two of the carrots and all of the onion, the celery, and the garlic (&amp;ldquo;roughly even proportions of onion, carrots, and celery&amp;rdquo;) Spread these out on the bottom of the instant pot Pile the meat on top Add salt (1 Tb per 2 lbs meat) Cover with water + 1 inch Pressure cook for 35 minutes (Mama does 45 minutes for 5 lbs) At end of cooking time, let sit for 10 minutes, then vent For the veggies (Add salt as you go)</description></item><item><title>Hungarian Mushroom Soup</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/hungarian_mushroom_soup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/hungarian_mushroom_soup/</guid><description>Original
Equipment Large soup pot Ingredients 1 stick (8 Tbsp) butter 4 cups onions, chopped (~2-3 medium onions?) 2 lb mushrooms, sliced 1 serrano chili, thinly sliced (optional) salt, to taste cayenne powder, to taste 1 cup dry white wine 4 cups chicken or vegetable stock Herbs: 1 Tbsp dried dill 1 Tbsp minced fresh thyme leaves Substitute or add: rosemary, tarragon, fresh sage. If fresh, can also just include whole sprig and fish it out later 1 Tbsp paprika 1/4 cup soy sauce 2 cup whole milk 1/3 cup flour 1/2 cup sour cream (or yogurt) 1/4 cup lemon juice optional goat cheese or parmesan for flavor (1/4 cup?</description></item><item><title>Broiled Salmon</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/broiled_salmon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/broiled_salmon/</guid><description>The Marinade 3 Tb minced onions (or scallions, or shallots) 1 1/2 Tb soy sauce 2 Tb olive oil 1/2 tsp rosemary (ground rosemary) 1 Tb rosemary to sprinkle Big pinch pepper or drops of Tabasco Black pepper (optional) The juice of 1/2 lemon A broiling pan Instructions Mix the marinade ingredients in a bowl (I run it through the food processor). Lay the salmon flat in the bottom of your broiling pan and spread on half the marinade.</description></item><item><title>Fondue</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/fondue/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/fondue/</guid><description>Stolen by Laura from Peter
Original
Equipment Fondue pot Fondue fuel Fondue forks Notes Most fondue pots can only handle 1200g of cheese mixture Best served with 1/2 small baguette per person Cut less than you think you will need to prevent left overs from going stale because the cheese is very filling Cheese can be substituted, just ask the cheese person at the store for a substitute for a fondue It is best to note start mixing the cheese until after guests arrive to avoid clumping Ingredients 200g gruyere 200g appenzeller 200ml &amp;ldquo;sekt&amp;rdquo; (sparkling wine?</description></item><item><title>Milk Rice (Rice Pudding/Arroz Doce)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/milk_rice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/milk_rice/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 cup rice 4 cups water 2-3 whole cloves 1/2 cup sugar (optional) Cinnamon to taste (optional) 4 cups milk 1 can sweetened condensed milk Instructions Add rice, water, and cloves to a pot and bring to a boil Turn down heat to low and cook for 20 minutes, all of the water should be gone; it will be like a thick soup, not like dry rice Add the sugar (if using), cinnamon, milk, and condensed milk, then cook on medium for 5 minutes</description></item><item><title>Goulash</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/goulash/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/goulash/</guid><description>Original
Ingredients Broth 2 lb Beef chuck 1 ts Salt 4 potatoes; Peeled and diced 2 Tbsp paprika 2 Tbsp olive oil 1/4 ts Black pepper 2 Bay Leaves 1 qt Water 2 onions Egg dumpling batter 1 Egg 6 tb Flour 1/8 tsp Salt Instructions Broth Cut beef into 1 inch squares, add 1/2 tsp. salt. Chop onions and brown in oil, add beef and paprika. Let beef simmer in its own juice along with salt and paprika for 1 hr.</description></item><item><title>Green Beans</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/green_beans/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/green_beans/</guid><description>Ingredients The ingredients below do not have quantities. Use amounts that you find tasty
Minced garlic (to taste) Red pepper flakes (to taste) (optional) toasted sesame seeds Extra virgin olive oil Sesame oil (a little goes a long way) Green beans Soy sauce (diluted in water so it&amp;rsquo;s not so strong) Instructions Saute minced garlic, red pepper flakes, and optionally toasted sesame seeds in a generous amount of extra virgin olive oil and bit of sesame oil Stir fry the green beans.</description></item><item><title>Tortillas</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/tortillas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/tortillas/</guid><description>Ingredients 10g oil 100g flour 55g water 1.5-2g salt (1/4 tsp) Instructions Mix all ingredients, oil first Roll out Cook</description></item><item><title>Beans (Brazilian)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/beans/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/beans/</guid><description>Equipment Pressure cooker Immersion blender (optional but makes things easier) Notes on pressure cooking The listed time to pressure cook something only starts counting from the moment pressure is achieved With an Instant Pot use high pressure, and make sure you turn the release valve to sealing instead of venting Ingredients Beans 3 cups beans (1 lb), unsoaked 9 cups water (3x cups beans) Seasoning 1 medium onion, diced small 3 cloves garlic, crushed olive oil, to taste salt, to taste 3/4 lb tomatoes, diced small Instructions Wash the beans, removing any rocks or particularly disfigured beans Combine beans and water in pressure cooker and pressure cook for 50 minutes While the beans are cooking, start the seasoning: Saute the onions until translucent, then add the garlic and saute another minute Add the tomatoes and salt and continue sauteing until the mixture has the consistency of a sauce, then set it aside Once the beans have finished pressure cooking, let them sit for 15 minutes to naturally release some of the pressure, then use whatever quick release method is safe to let off remaining pressure In a bowl (a liquid measuring cup works well for this) combine the seasoning and a few ladles of beans/bean broth Mix with the immersion blender, or sort of smash things with a wooden spoon if you don&amp;rsquo;t have one, then pour back into the rest of the beans Taste and adjust salt if necessary Bonus Serve some of the bean broth in shot glasses while it&amp;rsquo;s still hot.</description></item><item><title>Bolotas</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/bolotas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/bolotas/</guid><description>Original
Ingredients Dough 2 c flour 2 c milk 1/4 c mayonnaise 2 Tbsp grated parmesan cheese Tomato Sauce (1 lb per cup of flour) Onions Butter Diced tomatoes 1/2 c half and half Instructions Tomato Sauce Cook onions in butter Cook tomatoes for 15 minutes Put about 1/2 c half and half Make sure the sauce covers the bolotas generously Dough Boil the milk and mayonnaise When it boils, turn off the fire and mix in the flour and cheese Return pan to fire and keep stirring until it &amp;ldquo;looks right&amp;rdquo; Turn the fire off and let the mixture cool Make balls of the dough filled with chunks of mozzarella cheese Put in a glass pan, cover generously with sauce and bake in over for 30-40 minutes at 375 F Pictures</description></item><item><title>Chickpea Orzo Soup</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/chickpea_orzo_soup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/chickpea_orzo_soup/</guid><description>Original
Ingredients 1 lb chicken thigh, cut into 1/2-3/4 inch cubes 3 cloves garlic, pressed 1/2 tsp. dried thyme 1 tbsp. olive oil 1 onion, diced 3 large carrots, halved lengthwise and sliced 2 celery stalks, chopped 2-3 small stalks broccoli 6 cups vegetable broth + 1 cup water 2 14 oz cans chickpeas, rinsed and drained 1 small sprig rosemary 1 cup orzo 1 bay leaf 1/4 cup fresh lemon juice (~1 whole lemon) Instructions Saute the chicken with garlic and thyme, creating a nice frond.</description></item><item><title>Greek chicken</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/greek_chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/greek_chicken/</guid><description>Notes This recipe calls for chicken breast, but it can also be made with boneless skinless chicken thigh. Cooking the chicken breast can be a little tricky, and will end up a bit dry if you do it wrong. Chicken thigh is more forgiving. Ingredients 2 lbs chicken breast 1 Tbsp dried oregano Salt to taste (maybe 2 tsp?) 2 large or 4 medium cloves garlic, crushed Olive oil Instructions Into a large bowl, peel and crush the garlic.</description></item><item><title>Greek salad</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/greek_salad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/greek_salad/</guid><description>Notes I have no desire to specify amounts. Let your heart be your guiding key. Ingredients Tomatoes, medium dice Bell peppers, short strips Cucumber, peeled and diced Onion, minced Kalamata olives, sliced lengthwise Feta (either crumbled, or in small dice) Dried oregano Olive oil Salt, to taste (the feta and olives have salt, but you&amp;rsquo;ll still need a bit for the tomatoes/crosswords) Instructions Mix it all together and eat. Okay fine if I were doing it I&amp;rsquo;d probably start with the olive oil, oregano, salt, onion, and tomato, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think it really matters.</description></item><item><title>Osaka Sauce</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/osaka_sauce/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/osaka_sauce/</guid><description>Originally stolen from The Mustard Seed
Notes The sauce can be stored in the refrigerator for up to a month Ingredients 1 cup vegetable oil 2 1/2 Tbsp gingerroot, minced and peeled 1/2 rib celery, chopped 1/2 tsp sugar 1/4 cup sesame seeds, toasted 1/8 tsp celery seed (optional) Pinch white pepper 1/4 cup chopped onion 1/3 cup soy sauce 1/3 cup distilled white vinegar Instructions Using a blender, combine all ingredients except the soy sauce and vinegar.</description></item><item><title>Pasta primavera</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/pasta_prima/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/pasta_prima/</guid><description>Notes This is my absolute favorite recipe and a staple of my diet. I&amp;rsquo;ve made it my own over the years; feel free to do the same! The original recipe called for peeling the tomatoes, and left everything to marinate for an hour before the garlic was removed. I&amp;rsquo;ve removed these steps, but the order of operations in this recipe is designed to allow for maximum marination. However, these are guidelines, not rules&amp;ndash;nothing will be ruined if your prep timing lines up differently than the recipe calls for.</description></item><item><title>Persian Eggplant Stew (Khoresh-e Bademjoon)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/persian-eggplant-stew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/persian-eggplant-stew/</guid><description>Original 1 Original 2
Ingredients 1 lb boneless stew meat (lamb shoulder, beef cross rib roast, etc)
1 tsp turmeric (ground)
1 tsp salt
freshly ground black pepper, to taste
cayenne powder, to taste
olive oil
1 yellow onion, diced (1/2 for now, 1/2 for later)
2 lbs eggplant, any variety, peeled
olive oil
3 Tbsp tomato paste
(optional, Laura-only addition) 2lbs carrots, peeled and cut into 1/4 inch rounds</description></item><item><title>Quibe (Kibbeh)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/quibe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/quibe/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 lbs bulgar wheat (~5.5 cups) 5.5 cups of boiling water (1:1 with the bulgar wheat by volume) 4 lbs ground beef (2:1 meat to bulgar wheat by weight) 1 packet of mint (stems removed) 2 large onions Olive oil (enough to cover the onions similar to the amount needed for sauteing) 2 tbsp salt Instructions Preheat oven to 400 degrees. Set aside a 9x13 baking pan and a 9x9 baking pan.</description></item><item><title>Quiche Lorraine</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/quiche_lorraine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/quiche_lorraine/</guid><description>Notes Designed to feed 4 people This is designed for a pan that is not the American standard. For an American pan use only 3/4 of the ingredients below Gouda or Beemster Vlaskaas Cow&amp;rsquo;s Milk Cheese can be used as a substitute for Edamer Ingredients 200g (2.013c) flour 100g (6.972 Tbsp) butter 1/2 tsp salt 5 Tbsp water Butter to grease a springform pan 200g (7.055 oz) cooked ham 4 eggs 1/3L (1.</description></item><item><title>Smashed Potatoes</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/smashed_potatoes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/smashed_potatoes/</guid><description>Original
Ingredients TODO(laura): Make this recipe reasonable
2 lb. new or other small waxy potatoes 1 cup Diamond Crystal or ½ cup Morton kosher salt, plus more ⅔ cup extra-virgin olive oil, divided Freshly ground black pepper ½ cup walnuts, coarsely chopped 2 oil-packed anchovy fillets, drained 1 garlic clove 3 Tbsp. golden raisins 4 tsp. Aleppo-style or other mild red pepper flakes ¾ cup sour cream ½ cup mixed tender herbs, such as parsley, dill, cilantro, and/or basil Lemon wedges (for serving) Instructions TODO(laura): Make this recipe reasonable</description></item><item><title>Smoky Lentil Stew With Leeks</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/lentil_stew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/lentil_stew/</guid><description>Original
Ingredients 1½ cups small lentils, such as Pardina or Puy (12 ounces), or use any size green or brown lentil 1 medium onion, diced 2 bay leaves 2 whole cloves (*optional, I skip this) Kosher salt and black pepper 4 or 5 medium potatoes (*and/or 5 large carrots), peeled and sliced 3/4-inch thick 3 Tbsp extra-virgin olive oil, plus more for drizzling 2 medium leeks, white and tender green parts, chopped in 1/2-inch pieces 1 tsp chopped garlic (*just crush several cloves) 1 large thyme or rosemary sprig 2 Tbsp pimentón dulce or smoked sweet paprika ⅛ tsp ground cayenne, or to taste (*moar) Small pinch of saffron (about 12 strands), soaked in 1/4 cup cold water (*optional) 1 cup chopped canned tomato with juice 2 Tbsp sherry vinegar (can substitute red wine vinegar or apple cider vinegar) Chopped parsley (optional) Instructions Note: the lentils and leeks start out in two separate pots, then both end up in the same pot with the lentils.</description></item><item><title>Sue's Focaccia</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/sues_focaccia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/sues_focaccia/</guid><description>Copied directly from Sue
Notes I used 2 large onions, if you try it with 4 would you please let me know? I use half olive oil and half butter for carmelizing the onions The recipe for the dough uses a bread machine Ingredients Bread 3/4 cup water 2 tablespoonos olive or vegetable oil 2 cups bread flour 1 tablespoon sugar 1 teaspoon salt 1 1/2 teaspoons bread machine yeast For adding to Onion Topping later 3/4 cups (3 ounces) shredded mozzarella 2 tablespoons grated Parmesan cheese Onion Topping 1/8 cup butter 1/8 cup olive oil 2-4 large onions Instructions Bread Follow bread machine instructions and load bread ingredients in bread machine.</description></item><item><title>The one true rice</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/rice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/rice/</guid><description>Notes 1 cup of dry rice is probably 4 person-meals, give or take a person-meal. Ingredients X cups dry rice 2X cups water X/2 diced onions (potentially down to X/4 if it&amp;rsquo;s a really large onion) (medium-small dice) Oil (either olive oil or something flavorless, like canola) Salt, to taste (optional) Grated carrots, frozen peas, frozen corn, or other small vegetables. The amount doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter too much but maybe X/2 cups.</description></item></channel></rss>