<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recipes on mowery.dev</title><link>https://mowery.dev/categories/recipes/</link><description>Recent content in Recipes on mowery.dev</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 18:37:22 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mowery.dev/categories/recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hazelnut Macaroons (Nussmakronen)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/hazelnut_macaroons/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/hazelnut_macaroons/</guid><description>Original recipe (in German)
Ingredients 3 egg whites (no yolks!) 150g sugar (3/4 cup) (optional) 2 Tbsp vanilla sugar 250g ground hazelnuts (coarser than flour, but still pretty fine) (optional) whole hazelnuts for decoration parchment paper and/or something to grease a baking sheet with Instructions Preheat the oven to 150°C/300°F (or see step 8) Beat the egg whites a little, then add 1 Tbsp of sugar and beat fully stiff One spoon at a time, add the rest of the sugar (including vanilla sugar), and continue to beat for ~4 more minutes until the consistency is thick Gently fold in the ground hazelnuts (optional) Let the dough sit in the fridge for 30-60 minutes to get stiffer With two teaspoons, make small heaps on a greased and/or parchment-paper-lined baking sheet.</description></item><item><title>Milk Rice (Rice Pudding/Arroz Doce)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/milk_rice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/milk_rice/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 cup rice 4 cups water 2-3 whole cloves 1/2 cup sugar (optional) Cinnamon to taste (optional) 4 cups milk 1 can sweetened condensed milk Instructions Add rice, water, and cloves to a pot and bring to a boil Turn down heat to low and cook for 20 minutes, all of the water should be gone; it will be like a thick soup, not like dry rice Add the sugar (if using), cinnamon, milk, and condensed milk, then cook on medium for 5 minutes</description></item><item><title>Brigadeiros</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/brigadeiros/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/brigadeiros/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 Tbsp cocoa powder 1 Tbsp butter 14 oz sweetened condensed milk Chocolate sprinkles or crystal sugar Instructions In a medium saucepan over medium heat, combine cocoa, butter and condensed milk Cook, stirring the entire time, until thickened enough to show the pan bottom during stirring, about 10 minutes. When the pan is tipped, the mixture should appear to be loose from the pan Remove from heat and pour into a lightly greased dish Let rest until cool enough to handle, about two minutes Form into small balls (with greased hands) and roll over sprinkles or crystal sugar Place the balls in small candy cups and eat at once or chill until serving</description></item><item><title>Green Beans</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/green_beans/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/green_beans/</guid><description>Ingredients The ingredients below do not have quantities. Use amounts that you find tasty
Minced garlic (to taste) Red pepper flakes (to taste) (optional) toasted sesame seeds Extra virgin olive oil Sesame oil (a little goes a long way) Green beans Soy sauce (diluted in water so it&amp;rsquo;s not so strong) Instructions Saute minced garlic, red pepper flakes, and optionally toasted sesame seeds in a generous amount of extra virgin olive oil and bit of sesame oil Stir fry the green beans.</description></item><item><title>Tortillas</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/tortillas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/tortillas/</guid><description>Ingredients 10g oil 100g flour 55g water 1.5-2g salt (1/4 tsp) Instructions Mix all ingredients, oil first Roll out Cook</description></item><item><title>Beans (Brazilian)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/beans/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/beans/</guid><description>Equipment Pressure cooker Immersion blender (optional but makes things easier) Notes on pressure cooking The listed time to pressure cook something only starts counting from the moment pressure is achieved With an Instant Pot use high pressure, and make sure you turn the release valve to sealing instead of venting Ingredients Beans 3 cups beans (1 lb), unsoaked 9 cups water (3x cups beans) Seasoning 1 medium onion, diced small 3 cloves garlic, crushed olive oil, to taste salt, to taste 3/4 lb tomatoes, diced small Instructions Wash the beans, removing any rocks or particularly disfigured beans Combine beans and water in pressure cooker and pressure cook for 50 minutes While the beans are cooking, start the seasoning: Saute the onions until translucent, then add the garlic and saute another minute Add the tomatoes and salt and continue sauteing until the mixture has the consistency of a sauce, then set it aside Once the beans have finished pressure cooking, let them sit for 15 minutes to naturally release some of the pressure, then use whatever quick release method is safe to let off remaining pressure In a bowl (a liquid measuring cup works well for this) combine the seasoning and a few ladles of beans/bean broth Mix with the immersion blender, or sort of smash things with a wooden spoon if you don&amp;rsquo;t have one, then pour back into the rest of the beans Taste and adjust salt if necessary Bonus Serve some of the bean broth in shot glasses while it&amp;rsquo;s still hot.</description></item><item><title>Lime Mousse</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/lime_mousse/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/lime_mousse/</guid><description>Originally stolen from MOUSSE DE LIMÃO RÁPIDO
Ingredients 1 can (14 oz/400ml) sweetened condensed milk 400 ml whipping cream 1/2 c lime juice (4-5 limes) Instructions Beat condensed milk and cream in blender for three minutes, continue beating and add lime juice little by little, pour into bowl or prepared pie tin and let sit</description></item><item><title>Banana Bread (Grandma Lonergan's)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/banana_bread_matt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/banana_bread_matt/</guid><description>See original at matt9j.net/recipes/banana-bread
True origins unknown, but refined over many generations, this recipe makes a delicious soft banana bread. For maximum enjoyment be sure to not over-cook it, avoid over-mixing once you&amp;rsquo;ve combined the dry and wet ingredients, and consider adding some dark chocolate chips or favorite chopped nuts!
0: Prework: Preheat oven to 325 Lightly grease 9x5 loaf pan 1: In a large bowl mix: 2 cups flour 1 tsp baking soda ½ tsp baking powder ½ tsp salt 2: In a separate bowl mix: 1 ½ cup mashed overripe bananas (3-4) ¾ cup sugar ¾ cup vegetable oil 2 eggs 2 T vanilla (that is not a typo&amp;hellip; two tablespoons is correct) 3: Put it all together: Stir banana mixture into flour mixture; stir just to moisten.</description></item><item><title>Banana Bread (Laura)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/banana_bread_laura/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/banana_bread_laura/</guid><description>Original
Prework: Preheat oven to 325 Lightly grease 9x5 loaf pan
In a large bowl mix: 2 cups flour 1 tsp baking soda ½ tsp baking powder ½ tsp salt 1 T cinnamon In a separate bowl mix: 1½ cup mashed overripe bananas (3-4) 1/3 cup sugar ¾ cup vegetable oil 2 eggs 1 T vanilla Optionally some other fruit (e.g. 1-2 apples) cut small Put it all together: Stir banana mixture into flour mixture; stir just to moisten.</description></item></channel></rss>