<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Elise Bauer, With Adjustments by Laura Vonessen on mowery.dev</title><link>https://mowery.dev/author/elise-bauer-with-adjustments-by-laura-vonessen/</link><description>Recent content in Elise Bauer, With Adjustments by Laura Vonessen on mowery.dev</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 16:43:23 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mowery.dev/author/elise-bauer-with-adjustments-by-laura-vonessen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tomatillo Salsa Verde</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/tomatillo_salsa_verde/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/tomatillo_salsa_verde/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.simplyrecipes.com/recipes/tomatillo_salsa_verde/">Original&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="equipment">Equipment&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Pan for broiling tomatillos (can also just use regular baking sheet)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Foil for pan to make cleanup easier&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Blender and/or food processor for combining ingredients&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1.5 pounds tomatillos&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup chopped white onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 clove (or more) garlic, crushed (optional)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup chopped cilantro leaves and stems&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 lime (juice)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2-3 jalapeño or serrano peppers, (I use 3 whole serrano peppers, but you can also remove seeds if you want it less spicy)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt to taste (1/2 tsp?)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="instructions">Instructions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Preheat the broiler, setting the rack about 6 inches from the heating element.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the papery husks from the tomatillos and rinse well. Cut the tomatillos in half and place cut side down on a foil-lined baking sheet.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove stems from the peppers (and optionally seeds) and add them to the foil-lined sheet as well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place under a broiler for about 5-7 minutes to lightly blacken the skins of the tomatillos.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Roughly chop the onion, and squeeze the lime juice over it; set aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Combine half the cooked tomatillos, half the peppers, and all the rest of the ingredients (onions, lime, cilantro, crushed garlic, salt) in the blender or food processor, puree&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check spice and salt level&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the rest of the tomatillos, and as many of the rest of the peppers as you want based on the current spice level&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pulse until you reach desired chunkiness&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour salsa into bowl and mix to check for large chunks/tomatillo skins. If there are any chunks that are too large, return them to blender and pulse/puree. Repeat until satisfied.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cool, then refrigerate (or just eat it fresh, it&amp;rsquo;s delicious then too)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>