<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>family on mowery.dev</title><link>https://mowery.dev/tags/family/</link><description>Recent content in family on mowery.dev</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mowery.dev/tags/family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Banana Bread (Grandma Lonergan's)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/banana_bread_matt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/banana_bread_matt/</guid><description>See original at matt9j.net/recipes/banana-bread
True origins unknown, but refined over many generations, this recipe makes a delicious soft banana bread. For maximum enjoyment be sure to not over-cook it, avoid over-mixing once you&amp;rsquo;ve combined the dry and wet ingredients, and consider adding some dark chocolate chips or favorite chopped nuts!
0: Prework: Preheat oven to 325 Lightly grease 9x5 loaf pan 1: In a large bowl mix: 2 cups flour 1 tsp baking soda ½ tsp baking powder ½ tsp salt 2: In a separate bowl mix: 1 ½ cup mashed overripe bananas (3-4) ¾ cup sugar ¾ cup vegetable oil 2 eggs 2 T vanilla (that is not a typo&amp;hellip; two tablespoons is correct) 3: Put it all together: Stir banana mixture into flour mixture; stir just to moisten.</description></item><item><title>Waffles</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/waffles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/waffles/</guid><description>Laura&amp;rsquo;s waffle recipe, stolen from ancestors.
The portions here are for 2 people to eat a large breakfast.
If feeding more people double or triple the amounts below.
Equipment Blender Waffle iron that makes hearts Ingredients Number of people eating: Waffle batter 1/2 stick butter 2 eggs 1 pinch salt 1/4 cup sugar 3/4 cup oats 3/4 cup flour 1 cup milk (to right consistency) Mandated toppings Mixed frozen berries compote (no cherries), made by microwaving in a bowl for 3-4 minutes Maple syrup Powdered sugar Instructions Using a high powered blender To make the batter combine all ingredients in a blender and blend until consistent Using a shitty blender or making a larger recipe Cut the butter into pieces, combine with eggs, sugar, and salt in the blender and blend until consistent Add 1/4 cup flour, 1/4 cup oats, and 1/3 cup milk at a time, blend until consistent each time Pictures</description></item></channel></rss>