<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dessert on mowery.dev</title><link>https://mowery.dev/tags/dessert/</link><description>Recent content in dessert on mowery.dev</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 20:52:22 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mowery.dev/tags/dessert/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Strawberry Rhubarb Pie</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/strawberry_rhubarb_pie/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/strawberry_rhubarb_pie/</guid><description>Ingredients For the Filling 3 cups rhubarb in one-inch pieces, about one pound 2 cups strawberry halves ½ cup sugar 3 tablespoons corn starch or tapioca 3 tablespoons unsalted butter For the Crust 2½ cups all-purpose flour, plus more for dusting ½ teaspoon salt ¾ teaspoon sugar, plus extra for sprinkling 1 5tablespoons unsalted butter (almost 2 sticks), very cold and cut into ¼-inch cubes ½ cup ice-cold water 1 tablespoons milk Instructions Prepare the pastry: combine the flour, salt and sugar in a large mixing bowl.</description></item><item><title>Candied Orange and Lemon Peel</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/candied_orange_and_lemon_peel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/candied_orange_and_lemon_peel/</guid><description>Original
Prep Time: 20 mins Cook Time: 45 mins Total Time: 1 hr 5 mins
Ingredients Note
Yields approximately 8 ounces of candied citrus peel depending on peel thickness.
3 Valencia or Naval oranges and 4 lemons (can also use the equivalent of grapefruits, Meyer lemons and limes, or any citrus of your choice, thoroughly washed and scrubbed (as citrus is highly sprayed, I recommend using organic) 2 cups sugar 1 cup water Fine granulated sugar for coating Instructions Slice both ends of the citrus fruits.</description></item><item><title>Stollen</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/stollen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/stollen/</guid><description>Ingredients Dough 1 cup milk 1 egg 4 Tbsp butter 3 1/4 cups flour 1/2 cup (brown) sugar 1 tsp salt 1/2 tsp baking powder 1 1/2 tsp dry yeast Fruit and nuts 1/2 cup golden raisins 1/2 cup (3/4 cup) slivered almonds 1/2 cup candied fruit lemon zest (finely shredded peel) (optional) orange zest (finely shredded peel) (optional) Instructions Note
Using the sweet cycle of the bread machine (mine does the dough cycle in 1:20 min).</description></item><item><title>Hazelnut Macaroons (Nussmakronen)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/hazelnut_macaroons/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/hazelnut_macaroons/</guid><description>Original recipe (in German)
Ingredients 3 egg whites (no yolks!) 150g sugar (3/4 cup) (optional) 2 Tbsp vanilla sugar 250g ground hazelnuts (coarser than flour, but still pretty fine) (optional) whole hazelnuts for decoration parchment paper and/or something to grease a baking sheet with Instructions Preheat the oven to 150°C/300°F (or see step 8) Beat the egg whites a little, then add 1 Tbsp of sugar and beat fully stiff One spoon at a time, add the rest of the sugar (including vanilla sugar), and continue to beat for ~4 more minutes until the consistency is thick Gently fold in the ground hazelnuts (optional) Let the dough sit in the fridge for 30-60 minutes to get stiffer With two teaspoons, make small heaps on a greased and/or parchment-paper-lined baking sheet.</description></item><item><title>Milk Rice (Rice Pudding/Arroz Doce)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/milk_rice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/milk_rice/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 cup rice 4 cups water 2-3 whole cloves 1/2 cup sugar (optional) Cinnamon to taste (optional) 4 cups milk 1 can sweetened condensed milk Instructions Add rice, water, and cloves to a pot and bring to a boil Turn down heat to low and cook for 20 minutes, all of the water should be gone; it will be like a thick soup, not like dry rice Add the sugar (if using), cinnamon, milk, and condensed milk, then cook on medium for 5 minutes</description></item><item><title>Brigadeiros</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/brigadeiros/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/brigadeiros/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 Tbsp cocoa powder 1 Tbsp butter 14 oz sweetened condensed milk Chocolate sprinkles or crystal sugar Instructions In a medium saucepan over medium heat, combine cocoa, butter and condensed milk Cook, stirring the entire time, until thickened enough to show the pan bottom during stirring, about 10 minutes. When the pan is tipped, the mixture should appear to be loose from the pan Remove from heat and pour into a lightly greased dish Let rest until cool enough to handle, about two minutes Form into small balls (with greased hands) and roll over sprinkles or crystal sugar Place the balls in small candy cups and eat at once or chill until serving</description></item><item><title>Cheesecake (Julia)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/cheesecake/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/cheesecake/</guid><description>Ingredients Number of recipes: Crust 2 cups finely ground graham crackers (about 30 squares) 1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon 1 stick unsalted butter, melted Filling 1 pound cream cheese, softened 3 eggs 1 cup sugar 1 pint sour cream 1 lemon, zested 1 dash vanilla extract Warm Lemon Blueberries 1 pint blueberries 1 lemon, zested and juiced 2 tablespoons sugar Instructions Preheat the oven to 325 degrees F Crust In a mixing bowl, combine the ingredients with a fork until evenly moistened.</description></item><item><title>Lime Mousse</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/lime_mousse/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/lime_mousse/</guid><description>Originally stolen from MOUSSE DE LIMÃO RÁPIDO
Ingredients 1 can (14 oz/400ml) sweetened condensed milk 400 ml whipping cream 1/2 c lime juice (4-5 limes) Instructions Beat condensed milk and cream in blender for three minutes, continue beating and add lime juice little by little, pour into bowl or prepared pie tin and let sit</description></item><item><title>Banana Bread (Grandma Lonergan's)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/banana_bread_matt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/banana_bread_matt/</guid><description>See original at matt9j.net/recipes/banana-bread
True origins unknown, but refined over many generations, this recipe makes a delicious soft banana bread. For maximum enjoyment be sure to not over-cook it, avoid over-mixing once you&amp;rsquo;ve combined the dry and wet ingredients, and consider adding some dark chocolate chips or favorite chopped nuts!
0: Prework: Preheat oven to 325 Lightly grease 9x5 loaf pan 1: In a large bowl mix: 2 cups flour 1 tsp baking soda ½ tsp baking powder ½ tsp salt 2: In a separate bowl mix: 1 ½ cup mashed overripe bananas (3-4) ¾ cup sugar ¾ cup vegetable oil 2 eggs 2 T vanilla (that is not a typo&amp;hellip; two tablespoons is correct) 3: Put it all together: Stir banana mixture into flour mixture; stir just to moisten.</description></item><item><title>Banana Bread (Laura)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/banana_bread_laura/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/banana_bread_laura/</guid><description>Original
Prework: Preheat oven to 325 Lightly grease 9x5 loaf pan
In a large bowl mix: 2 cups flour 1 tsp baking soda ½ tsp baking powder ½ tsp salt 1 T cinnamon In a separate bowl mix: 1½ cup mashed overripe bananas (3-4) 1/3 cup sugar ¾ cup vegetable oil 2 eggs 1 T vanilla Optionally some other fruit (e.g. 1-2 apples) cut small Put it all together: Stir banana mixture into flour mixture; stir just to moisten.</description></item><item><title>Carrot Cake</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/carrot_cake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/carrot_cake/</guid><description>Original
Equipment Stand mixer 2 9 inch round cake pans Ingredients Carrot Cake 2 cups (250 grams) all-purpose flour 2 teaspoons baking soda 1/2 teaspoon fine sea salt 1 tablespoon ground cinnamon 1 1/4 cups (295 ml) canola or other vegetable oil 1 cup (200 grams) granulated sugar 1 cup (200 grams) lightly packed brown sugar 1 teaspoon vanilla extract 4 large eggs 3 cups (300 grams) grated peeled carrots (5 to 6 medium carrots) 1 cup (100 grams) coarsely chopped pecans 1/2 cup (65 grams) raisins Frosting 8 ounces (225 grams) cream cheese, at room temperature 1 1/4 cups (140 grams) powdered sugar 1/3 cup (80 ml) heavy whipping cream 1/2 cup (50 grams) coarsely chopped pecans, for topping cake Instructions Batter Heat the oven to 350 degrees Fahrenheit (176C).</description></item><item><title>Cinnamon Rolls</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/cinnamon_rolls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/cinnamon_rolls/</guid><description>Original
Ingredients Cinnamon Rolls 4 1/2 teaspoons active dry yeast (2 packets) 1 cup lukewarm water 1 teaspoon granulated sugar, to proof the yeast 6 tablespoons shortening or unsalted butter 1 cup granulated sugar 9 cups unbleached all-purpose flour (more if the dough is sticky, up to 10 cups) 2 cups hot water 2 large eggs, beaten 1 tablespoon salt 1/2 cup softened butter, divided 1 1/2 cups brown sugar, divided 1 cup raisins 1 cup pecans 2 tablespoons ground cinnamon, divided 1 cup heavy cream Frosting 1/4 cup unsalted butter, softened 4 cups powdered sugar 4 tablespoons milk, more if necessary 1 teaspoon vanilla extract Instructions In a small bowl, combine the yeast and a pinch of the granulated sugar with the lukewarm water and set aside for 5 minutes or until the yeast bubbles up.</description></item><item><title>Cobbler</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/cobbler/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/cobbler/</guid><description>Original
Ingredients Filling 4 cups frozen mixed berries*, NOT thawed (about 24 ounces frozen fruit) 3 tablespoons granulated sugar 3 tablespoons all purpose flour zest from 1/2 lemon pinch of salt Topping 1 cup old fashioned rolled oats 1/2 cup brown sugar 6 tablespoons all purpose flour 1 stick (1/2 cup) salted butter, cold, cut into small cubes Instructions Preheat oven to 350 degrees with the oven in the middle position.</description></item><item><title>Lemon bars</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/lemon_bars/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/lemon_bars/</guid><description>Original
Ingredients 3 cups all-purpose flour divided 2 1/2 cups for crust and 1/2 cup for filling 2/3 cups powdered sugar for the shortbread, plus more for dusting 1/2 tsp salt 12 tbsp unsalted butter melted 3 tbsp lemon zest, zest of three lemons 3 cups sugar 8 eggs large, room temperature 1 cup lemon juice fresh Instructions Heat oven to 350F and line a 9x13 baking dish with parchment paper.</description></item><item><title>Lime Mousse Pie</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/lime_mousse_pie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/lime_mousse_pie/</guid><description>Notes This recipe makes 2 8-inch pies or 1 9-inch pie. Ingredients 1.5 cups of graham crackers 6 tbsp butter 1/3 cup sugar Ingredients for Lime Mousse Instructions Food process the graham crackers into a fine crumble, then dump the crumbs into a mixing bowl Food process the butter and sugar together, then add them to the graham crackers Pat the mixture into a pie tin Follow the recipe for the lime mousse, then pour the result over the pie tin Let set in the freezer Images</description></item><item><title>Ma' Johnson's Fresh Blueberry Pie</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/blueberry_pie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/blueberry_pie/</guid><description>See original at matt9j.net/recipes/blueberry-pie
Adapted and customized from a recipe appearing in a 1940&amp;rsquo;s cookbook, this recipe really hits the spot during summer fresh blueberry season.
You can make it as a traditional pie with a top crust, but the real magic is when you replace the top crust with the optional streusel topping detailed below.
Pie Instructions Preheat oven to 425F. Prepare pie crust. In large bowl, combine blueberries, sugar, flour and cinnamon; toss lightly to mix.</description></item><item><title>Plum Cake (Pflaumenkuchen)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/plum_cake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/plum_cake/</guid><description>Notes: For historical reasons this is named &amp;ldquo;Plum Cake&amp;rdquo; but it is actually a pie. This is our version of Pflaumenkuchen. Ingredients Wet ingredients 1 stick butter (1/2 cup) 1 egg 2/3c sugar Dry ingredients 1 1/2c flour 1/2 Tbsp baking powder 1 pinch salt 1/2 cinnamon Plums 1.5 lbs italian plums, halved The topping 1 tsp cinnamon 1/4c hazelnuts (After baking, optional) 1 Tbsp cane sugar Instructions Preheat oven to 375*F.</description></item></channel></rss>