<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Regina Souza on mowery.dev</title><link>https://mowery.dev/author/regina-souza/</link><description>Recent content in Regina Souza on mowery.dev</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 16:00:07 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mowery.dev/author/regina-souza/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beef Veggie Soup</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/beef_veggie_soup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/beef_veggie_soup/</guid><description>(as interpreted by Laura, and then halved)
Ingredients 2.5 lb cubed stew meat or beef shank ½ onion 2 stalks/ribs celery (not 2 heads!) 2 cloves garlic 8 carrots (peeled, 2 in food processor, others in large chunks) (for original double recipe, 10-15 carrots) ½ butternut squash, peeled and cut in cubes (can also use 1 lb pre-cut) 1 large or 2 small sweet potatoes (pale yellow), peeled and cut in cubes 1 lb green beans, cut into halves or thirds and with ends removed For the meat Food-process two of the carrots and all of the onion, the celery, and the garlic (&amp;ldquo;roughly even proportions of onion, carrots, and celery&amp;rdquo;) Spread these out on the bottom of the instant pot Pile the meat on top Add salt (1 Tb per 2 lbs meat) Cover with water + 1 inch Pressure cook for 35 minutes (Mama does 45 minutes for 5 lbs) At end of cooking time, let sit for 10 minutes, then vent For the veggies (Add salt as you go)</description></item><item><title>Spiced Cider</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/spiced_cider/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/spiced_cider/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 gallon apple cider 6 cinnamon sticks 1 tsp whole black peppercorns 1/2 inch ginger, thinly sliced 3 round orange slices Instructions Place peppercorns and ginger in a tea infuser Pour all other ingredients, plus tea infuser, into a pot that can comfortably hold a gallon Bring to a boil, and then let simmer for 20 minutes Enjoy! (or else)</description></item><item><title>Candied Orange and Lemon Peel</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/candied_orange_and_lemon_peel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/candied_orange_and_lemon_peel/</guid><description>Original
Prep Time: 20 mins Cook Time: 45 mins Total Time: 1 hr 5 mins
Ingredients Note
Yields approximately 8 ounces of candied citrus peel depending on peel thickness.
3 Valencia or Naval oranges and 4 lemons (can also use the equivalent of grapefruits, Meyer lemons and limes, or any citrus of your choice, thoroughly washed and scrubbed (as citrus is highly sprayed, I recommend using organic) 2 cups sugar 1 cup water Fine granulated sugar for coating Instructions Slice both ends of the citrus fruits.</description></item><item><title>Stollen</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/stollen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/stollen/</guid><description>Ingredients Dough 1 cup milk 1 egg 4 Tbsp butter 3 1/4 cups flour 1/2 cup (brown) sugar 1 tsp salt 1/2 tsp baking powder 1 1/2 tsp dry yeast Fruit and nuts 1/2 cup golden raisins 1/2 cup (3/4 cup) slivered almonds 1/2 cup candied fruit lemon zest (finely shredded peel) (optional) orange zest (finely shredded peel) (optional) Instructions Note
Using the sweet cycle of the bread machine (mine does the dough cycle in 1:20 min).</description></item><item><title>Broiled Salmon</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/broiled_salmon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/broiled_salmon/</guid><description>The Marinade 3 Tb minced onions (or scallions, or shallots) 1 1/2 Tb soy sauce 2 Tb olive oil 1/2 tsp rosemary (ground rosemary) 1 Tb rosemary to sprinkle Big pinch pepper or drops of Tabasco Black pepper (optional) The juice of 1/2 lemon A broiling pan Instructions Mix the marinade ingredients in a bowl (I run it through the food processor). Lay the salmon flat in the bottom of your broiling pan and spread on half the marinade.</description></item><item><title>French Toast</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/french_toast/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/french_toast/</guid><description> Info
This recipe involves leaving the bread in the fridge overnight, plan accordingly
Equipment Requires a large pan (10x15) Ingredients 6 Le Petit Outre Kaiser Rolls (top and bottom crust removed) 6 eggs 2 cups of milk 3/8 cup sugar 1/2 tsp salt 1 Tbsp Vanilla 2 Tbsp Butter (cut into thin slices) Cinnamon (to taste) Instructions Grease pan; place the bread Beat eggs, sugar, salt, vanilla Pour the mixture on the bread Leave overnight in fridge Turn the bread around (so the top gets moister) Sprinkle Cinnamon Put thin slices of butter on top Bake for about 40 minutes (to an hour) on 350 F (325 F if on a glass dish)</description></item><item><title>Goulash</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/goulash/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/goulash/</guid><description>Original
Ingredients 2 lb beef chuck (anything labeled stew meat works) 1 tsp salt 2lb potatoes, peeled and diced 1lb carrots, peeled and chopped (non-traditional but delicious) 2 Tbsp paprika 2 Tbsp olive oil 1/4 tsp black pepper 2 bay leaves 2 onions, diced 2 bell peppers, diced 1-2 diced tomato cans Instructions Chop onions and brown in oil Add chopped bell peppers and tomatoes to onions and saute until softened Add beef (chopped into 1 inch squares), ground paprika, and bay leaves.</description></item><item><title>Green Beans</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/green_beans/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/green_beans/</guid><description>Ingredients The ingredients below do not have quantities. Use amounts that you find tasty
Minced garlic (to taste) Red pepper flakes (to taste) (optional) toasted sesame seeds Extra virgin olive oil Sesame oil (a little goes a long way) Green beans Soy sauce (diluted in water so it&amp;rsquo;s not so strong) Instructions Saute minced garlic, red pepper flakes, and optionally toasted sesame seeds in a generous amount of extra virgin olive oil and bit of sesame oil Stir fry the green beans.</description></item><item><title>Cheese bread (pão de queijo)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/cheese_bread/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/cheese_bread/</guid><description>Equipment Mini Muffin tins Notes When using a shitty blender make 2/3 Ingredients 3 eggs 1 cup oil (bland) 1 cup milk 1/2 tablespoon salt 1.5 cups parmesan cheese 3 cups tapioca flour Instructions Grease mini muffin tin Mix liquid ingredients in blender Mix in dry ingredients Fill 2/3 of each mini muffin tin with batter Bake for 20-25 minutes at 350 degrees</description></item></channel></rss>