<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>soup on mowery.dev</title><link>https://mowery.dev/tags/soup/</link><description>Recent content in soup on mowery.dev</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mowery.dev/tags/soup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hungarian Mushroom Soup</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/hungarian_mushroom_soup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/hungarian_mushroom_soup/</guid><description>Original
Equipment Large soup pot Ingredients 1 stick (8 Tbsp) butter 4 cups onions, chopped (~2-3 medium onions?) 2 lb mushrooms, sliced 1 serrano chili, thinly sliced (optional) salt, to taste cayenne powder, to taste 1 cup dry white wine 4 cups chicken or vegetable stock Herbs: 1 Tbsp dried dill 1 Tbsp minced fresh thyme leaves Substitute or add: rosemary, tarragon, fresh sage. If fresh, can also just include whole sprig and fish it out later 1 Tbsp paprika 1/4 cup soy sauce 2 cup whole milk 1/3 cup flour 1/2 cup sour cream (or yogurt) 1/4 cup lemon juice optional goat cheese or parmesan for flavor (1/4 cup?</description></item><item><title>Chickpea Orzo Soup</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/chickpea_orzo_soup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/chickpea_orzo_soup/</guid><description>Original
Ingredients 1 lb chicken thigh, cut into 1/2-3/4 inch cubes 3 cloves garlic, pressed 1/2 tsp. dried thyme 1 tbsp. olive oil 1 onion, diced 3 large carrots, halved lengthwise and sliced 2 celery stalks, chopped 2-3 small stalks broccoli 6 cups vegetable broth + 1 cup water 2 14 oz cans chickpeas, rinsed and drained 1 small sprig rosemary 1 cup orzo 1 bay leaf 1/4 cup fresh lemon juice (~1 whole lemon) Instructions Saute the chicken with garlic and thyme, creating a nice frond.</description></item><item><title>Persian Eggplant Stew (Khoresh-e Bademjoon)</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/persian-eggplant-stew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/persian-eggplant-stew/</guid><description>Original 1 Original 2
Ingredients 1 lb boneless stew meat (lamb shoulder, beef cross rib roast, etc)
1 tsp turmeric (ground)
1 tsp salt
freshly ground black pepper, to taste
cayenne powder, to taste
olive oil
1 yellow onion, diced (1/2 for now, 1/2 for later)
2 lbs eggplant, any variety, peeled
olive oil
3 Tbsp tomato paste
(optional, Laura-only addition) 2lbs carrots, peeled and cut into 1/4 inch rounds</description></item><item><title>Smoky Lentil Stew With Leeks</title><link>https://mowery.dev/recipes/lentil_stew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mowery.dev/recipes/lentil_stew/</guid><description>Original
Ingredients 1½ cups small lentils, such as Pardina or Puy (12 ounces), or use any size green or brown lentil 1 medium onion, diced 2 bay leaves 2 whole cloves (*optional, I skip this) Kosher salt and black pepper 4 or 5 medium potatoes (*and/or 5 large carrots), peeled and sliced 3/4-inch thick 3 Tbsp extra-virgin olive oil, plus more for drizzling 2 medium leeks, white and tender green parts, chopped in 1/2-inch pieces 1 tsp chopped garlic (*just crush several cloves) 1 large thyme or rosemary sprig 2 Tbsp pimentón dulce or smoked sweet paprika ⅛ tsp ground cayenne, or to taste (*moar) Small pinch of saffron (about 12 strands), soaked in 1/4 cup cold water (*optional) 1 cup chopped canned tomato with juice 2 Tbsp sherry vinegar (can substitute red wine vinegar or apple cider vinegar) Chopped parsley (optional) Instructions Note: the lentils and leeks start out in two separate pots, then both end up in the same pot with the lentils.</description></item></channel></rss>